{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.RC coupled amplifier1.Very low driftB.Tuned amplifier2.Flat frequency response from zero frequency onwardsC.Chopper stabilized amplifier3.Flat frequency response with upper and lower cut off frequencyD.DC amplifier4.Peak in gain frequency response", "opta": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "optb": "A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: Microwave Measuring Instruments Measurements EffectedA.Bolometer1.Reflection coefficientsB.VSWR meter2.Half power beam widthsC.Cavity wave meter3.Microwave powerD.Pattern recorder4.Microwave frequency", "opta": "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3", "optb": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", "optc": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optd": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Circuit)  List II (Characteristics) A.Darlington pair1.uses pnp and npn transistors used as power amplifierB.CB amplifier2.Voltage gain nearly 1 and high input impedanceC.Cascade amplifier3.low input impedance used for high frequency isolation", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1", "optc": "A-2, B-1, C-3", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (FET Parameters)  List II (Typical Values) A.gm for JFET1.25 kWB.rd for JFET2.0.01 siemenC.rd for MOSFET3.0.5 mWD.gg for JFET4.10-8 siemen", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optd": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Word wrap1.interleaved execution of two or more programs by the same computerB.Client2.automatically moves a word to the next line if it does not fit in the current lineC.Multitasking3.an application receiving dataD.Landscape4.orientation of worksheet", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-4, D-1", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Camera pick up tubes)  List II (Developed by) A.CCD charger1.ToshibaB.New vicon2.PhilipsC.Plumbicon3.MatushitaD.Chalnicon4.RCA", "opta": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optb": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (DOS commands)  List II (Meaning) A.ATTRIB1.Displays all directories and subdirectoriesB.SCAN DISK2.Moves files to another directorC.MOVE3.Checks the status of discD.TREE4.Hides a file", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-2, B-3, C-4, D-1", "optd": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.1.ZeroB.2.0.2C.3.ActuatorD.4.infinity", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Horn antenna1.High directivityB.Parabolic antenna2.Very high directivityC.Lens antenna3.Moderate directivity", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "optc": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "optd": "A-1, B-3, C-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.TV1.1 kHzB.Radio2.3 kHzC.Telephony3.9 kHzD.Telegraphy4.5 MHz", "opta": "A-4, B-1, C-2", "optb": "A-4, B-3, C-2", "optc": "A-2, B-1, C-3", "optd": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (fk) List II [F(z)] A.11.B.kn2.(1 - az-1)-1C.ak3.- ln (1 - z-1)-1D.4.(1 - z-1)-1", "opta": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-1, C-2, D-3", "optd": "A-1, B-4, C-3, D-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.p type semiconductor1.siliconB.n type semiconductor2.holes are majority carriersC.Intrinsic semiconductor3.electrons are majority carriersD.Tungsten4.is a metal", "opta": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-2, D-4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Resistance1.M-1L-2T2I2B.Inductance2.ML2T-2I-2C.Capacitance3.M-1L-2T4I2D.Reluctance4.ML2T-3I-2", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-1, C-3, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optd": "A-2, B-4, C-3, D-1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Octal)  List II (Decimal number)A.351.53B.652.62C.543.29D.764.44", "opta": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optc": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Instrument)  List II (Measured quantity) A.Hot wire1.only voltageB.PMMC2.phaseC.Electrostatic3.true RMS valueD.Lock in Amplifier4.dc value", "opta": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", "optb": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optc": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-2, B-3, C-4, D-1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Laws of Boolean)  List II (Relation algebra) A.Distributive law1.x + x = xB.DeMorgans law2.x(y + z) = xy + xzC.Idempotent law3.(x) = xD.Involution law4.(x + y) = xy", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optc": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-4, B-1, C-2, D-3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Library function in Pascal)  List II (Type of argument)A.ROUND X1.X in radiansB.ABS X2.X realC.SQR X3.X real or integerD.SIN X", "opta": "A-2, B-3, C-3, D-1", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-3", "optc": "A-3, B-2, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-2, B-3, C-2, D-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I f(t) List II F (s)A.cos \u03c9t1.B.sin \u03c9t2.C.cosh \u03c9t3.D.sinh \u03c9t4.", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-4, B-2, C-1, D-3", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Resistance1.Current noiseB.Diode2.Partition noiseC.Triode3.Shot noiseD.p-n junction4.Atmospheric noise  5.Johnson noise", "opta": "A-5, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-5", "optc": "A-3, B-5, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-3, B-5, C-2, D-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Command in WORD)  List II (Meaning) A.END1.The bar displays the current position of cursorB.HOME2.Moves cursor to the beginning of current lineC.Status3.Moves cursor to end of document", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "optc": "A-2, B-3, C-1", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Operator in C)  List II (Priority of Operation) A.!1.1B.< >2.2C.\u22173.3D.=4.4", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Oscillator)  List II (Features) A.Wien Bridge1.RF oscillator, uses two inductors and one capacitorB.Colpitt's2.LC oscillator for radio frequencies uses three capacitances and one inductanceC.Hartley3.RC oscillator for audio frequenciesD.Clapp4.RF oscillator, uses two capacitances and one inductance", "opta": "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3", "optb": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optc": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Symbol in java)  List II (Meaning)A.&1.Logical ANDB.\u02c62.ANDC.| |3.XORD.& &4.Logical OR", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optd": "A-2, B-3, C-4, D-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.RT1.A = DB.Rh2.h12 = h21C.ST3.AD - BC = 1D.Sh4.h21 = - h21  5.B = C  6.\u0394h = 1", "opta": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-6", "optb": "A-3, B-2, C-5, D-4", "optc": "A-5, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-5, B-4, C-1, D-6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Network parameter)  List II (Measured under open-circuit conditions) A.Z111.B.A2.C.C3.D.Z224.", "opta": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optb": "A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-1, B-2, C-4, D-3", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-4, D-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.SSB Modulation1.Transmission lineB.\u0394 . B = 02.Hilbert transformC.Model dispersion3.Faraday's law  4.Absence of magnetic monopoles  5.Waveguides  6.Phase locked loop", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-5", "optb": "A-5, B-4, C-2", "optc": "A-6, B-4, C-5", "optd": "A-2, B-4, C-5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.1.B.2.C.3.D.4.", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (type of controller) List II (Operation)A.Pneumatic controller1.Flexible operationB.Hydraulic controller2.High torque high speed operationC.Electronic controller3.Fire and explosion proof operation", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optc": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I f(t)  List II F(s) A.t1.B.eat2.C.u(t)3.D.cos \u03c9t4.", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optc": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optd": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.DIAC1.B.TRIAC2.C.SIT3.D.LASCR4.", "opta": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optc": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Comm.services) List II (Bandwidth) A.AM broadcast1.10 kHzB.Telephone2.4 kHzC.wide-band FM3.200 kHzD.TV4.7 MHz", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optc": "A-1, B-4, C-3, D-2", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Logic family)  List II (Characteristic of logic family) A.TTL1.Maximum power ConsumptionB.ECL2.Highest Packing DensityC.NMOS3.Least Power ConsumptionD.CMOS4.Saturated Logic", "opta": "A-1, B-4, C-2, D-3", "optb": "A-1, B-4, C-3, D-2", "optc": "A-4, B-1, C-2, D-3", "optd": "A-4, B-1, C-3, D-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Penetration frequency1.Lowest frequency at which charged particles spiral in fixed magnetic fieldB.Optimum working frequency2.Same as critical and frequencyC.Gyro frequency3.Highest frequency of radio waves that can be usedD.Maximum usable frequency4.The most effective frequency for ionosphere propagation of radio waves", "opta": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optb": "A-4, B-1, C-3, D-2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Synchro1.AmplifierB.Amplidyne2.ActuatorC.Servo3.CompensatorD.RC network4.Transducer", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-3, B-2, C-4, D-1", "optd": "A-4, B-1, C-2, D-3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Silicon1.is trivalentB.Arsenic2.rarely used as semiconductorC.Indium3.is pentavalentD.Germanium4.intrinsic semiconductor", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-2, B-1, C-3, D-4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.VOH(min)1.2.4 VB.VIH(min)2.1.5 VC.VOL(max)3.0.4 V  4.2.0 V  5.0.8 V", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-4", "optb": "A-1, B-4, C-3", "optc": "A-5, B-4, C-3", "optd": "A-1, B-5, C-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.n Channel JFET1.B.p Channel JFET2.C.Depletion MOSFET3.D.Enhancement MOSFET4.", "opta": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optb": "A-1, B-3, C-4, D-2", "optc": "A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2", "optd": "A-2, B-4, C-3, D-1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Ring modulator1.Clock recoveryB.VCO2.Demodulation of FMC.Foster Seeley discriminator3.Frequency conversionD.Mixer4.Summing of two points  5.Generation of FM  6.Generation of DSB-SC", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-6, B-5, C-2, D-3", "optc": "A-6, B-1, C-3, D-2", "optd": "A-5, B-6, C-1, D-3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Serial Binary adder1.(2n - 1)tpdB.Ripple carry adder2.(n - 1)tpdC.Carry look ahead binary adder3.Operation time independent of size  4.6tpd for 4 bit carry look ahead adder", "opta": "A-2, B-1, C-3", "optb": "A-2, B-1, C-4", "optc": "A-1, B-2, C-4", "optd": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Zener diode1.B.Tunnel diode2.C.Schottky diode3.D.Diode4.", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optc": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-4, D-1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Instrument)  List II (Parameters) A.Moving coil galvanometer1.High inertia, soft spring controlB.Ballistic galvanometer2.No control, high dampingC.Vibration galvanometer3.Soft spring control, critical dampingD.Moving coil flux meter4.Low inertia, tuned spring control", "opta": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optb": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optc": "A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Output of signal generator1.ModulatedB.Error signal from a synchro2.DigitalC.Output of a JK flip flop3.AnalogD.Signal received by radar4.Stoichastic", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-3, B-1, C-2, D-4", "optc": "A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2", "optd": "A-1, B-3, C-4, D-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Types of transmission structure)  List II (Modes of propagation)A.Strip line1.Quasi TEMB.Hollow rectangular waveguide2.Pure TEMC.Microstrip3.TE/TMD.Corrugated waveguide4.Hybrid", "opta": "A-2, B-1, C-3, D-4", "optb": "A-4, B-1, C-3, D-2", "optc": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optd": "A-4, B-3, C-1, D-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (\u03bcP)  List II (Number of bits in register) A.80851.32 bitB.80862.16 bitC.680003.8/16 bit", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1", "optc": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "optd": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (DOS commands)  List II (Meaning) A.DBLSPACE1.Deletes a director and its sub-directoriesB.MEM2.Displays the amount of used and free memoryC.SYS3.Put a copy of DOS on diskD.DELTREE4.Compresses files to increase the storage capacity of disc", "opta": "A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-4, D-1", "optc": "A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1", "optd": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Zener diode1.used in seven segment displayB.Tunnel diode2.used in voltage regulator circuitsC.LED3.used is solar energy utilizationD.Photovoltaic cell4.used in digital circuits", "opta": "A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optc": "A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3", "optd": "A-3, B-2, C-4, D-1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.Reactance theorem1.FosterB.Driving point impedance2.BartlettC.Continued fraction expansion3.CauerD.Bisection Theorem4.Positive real function", "opta": "A-1, B-4, C-3, D-2", "optb": "A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4", "optc": "A-2, B-3, C-1, D-4", "optd": "A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I (Operator)  List II (Description) A.& &1.AssignmentB.| |2.Logical ANDC.=3.Logical OR", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1", "optc": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "optd": "A-1, B-3, C-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.shift Register1.Frequency divisionB.Counter2.Addressing in memory chipsC.Decoder3.Serial to parallel Data conversion", "opta": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "optb": "A-3, B-1, C-2", "optc": "A-2, B-1, C-3", "optd": "A-1, B-2, C-2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Match the following: List I  List II A.DMA controller1.Interface between computer and video display adapterB.CKT controller2.Used to read data directly from disk into directly memoryC.Interrupt controller3.Supervises the operation of control signal", "opta": "A-1, B-2, C-3", "optb": "A-2, B-3, C-1", "optc": "A-3, B-2, C-1", "optd": "A-2, B-1, C-3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}